[
{
 "question" : "What is the significance of the 0th law of thermodynamics? Why is it the 0th law if it is important?",
 "answer" : "The 0th law essentially says that temperature is an important indicator of thermal equilibrium. The 0th defines temperature as the following: if two bodies with the same temperature were to touch one another, no heat exchange would occur.",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference": "https://www.vedantu.com/question-answer/mention-the-significance-of-zeroth-law-class-11-physics-cbse-5f224ae5c022a73b14d72501"
 },

{"question": "For a steady flow that is adiabatic and reversible, why is the work defined by mass x cp x delta T and not m x cv x delta T?",
 "answer": "The first law for a closed system states that delta U = Q - W. For an adiabatic system we see that delta U = -W and derive that W = -cp x delta T. The steady flow energy equation however, is for an open system where we choose a control volume.",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference":""
 },

{
 "question" : "A frictionless piston-cylinder device contains 10 lbm of steam at 60 psia and 320F. Heat is now transferred to the steam until the temperature reaches 400F. If the piston is not attached to a shaft and its mass is constant, determine the work done by the steam during this process.",
 "answer" : "\n    import numpy as np\n    \n    # We assume that the pressure remains constant and that the expansion process is quasi-equilibrium\n    # for a constant pressure process, W = P delta V\n    P0 = 60 # pressure \n    # V = mv since we can look up the specific volumes.\n    v1 = 7.4863 #specific volume at the given pressure and temperature\n    v2 = 8.3548\n    m = 10\n    conversionFactor = 5.404\n    W = round((m * P0 *(v2-v1))/conversionFactor,3) \n    print('The work done by the steam during this process is',W, 'Btu') \n    ",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference": "Michael Boles and Yunus Cengel (2010) Thermodynamics an Engineering Approach. Chapter 4.1 Moving Boundary Work, Example 4-2."
     },
    
{
 "question": "A piston-cylinder device contains a liquid-vapor mixture of water at 300K. During a constant pressure process, 750 kJ of heat is transferred to the water. As a result, part of the liquid in the cylinder vaporizes. Determine the entropy change of the water during this process.",
 "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    \n    # Assume that no irreversibilities occur within the sustem boundaries within the process.\n    # Take all the water (liquid and vapor) in the cylinder as the system.\n    T = 300 # temperature in Kelvins\n    Q = 350 # heat in kJ\n    delta_S = round(Q/T,2) \n    print('The entropy change of the system is',delta_S,'kJs/K.')\n    ",
 "explanation": "This code calculates the change in entropy using the definition of change in entropy delta_S = heat divided by temperature.",
 "reference" : "Michael Boles and Yunus Cengel(2010) Thermodynamics an Engineering Approach. Chapter 7.1 Entropy, Example 7-1."
 },

{
 "question": "Can you give an example of a reversible adiabatic process and an irreversible adiabatic process?",
 "answer": "A reversible adiabatic process could be the expansion of steam in steam turbines. An example of an irreversible adiabatic process could be the expansion of a gas into a vacuum. For example, imagine a vacuum in a lab that gets ruptured and air gets in. Because the gas enters so suddenly, there is no time for heat exchange and because of entropy, the ruptured chamber cannot go back to a vacuum.",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference":""
 },

{
 "question": "Why should I care about the Navier-Stokes Equations?",
 "answer": "The Navier-Stokes Equations can describe the flow incompressible fluids taking into account viscosity. The equation is too complex to completely solve in three-dimensional fluid flows but supposing they can be solved, the Navier-Stokes equations pose to be a powerful tool in predicting flows. The question of whether smooth, reasonable solutions to the Navier-Stokes equations in three dimensions was designated as a Millennium Problem in 2000 and a reward of $1 million USD is attached to its solution",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference":""
 },

{
 "question": "The flow velocity in the test section of a low-speed subsonic wind tunnel is 100 mph. The test section is vented to the atmosphere, where atmospheric pressure is 1.01 x 10^5 N/m^2. The density in the flow is the standard sea level value of 1.23 kg/m^3. The contraction ratio of the nozzle is 10-to-1. Calculate the resevoir pressure in the atmosphere.",
 "answer": "\n     import numpy as np\n         \n     # First we must convert our units to the proper ones. \n     V_mph = 100 # given velocity, in miles per hour\n     V_ms = (V_mph * 1609) / 3600 # velocity converted to meters per second\n     rho = 1.23 # density in kg/m^3\n     A_2 = 10\n     A_1 = 1 # area ratio is given to be 10-to-1\n     p2 = 1.01 * 10**5 # athmospheric pressure in N/m^2\n     p1 = round(p2 + ((rho*(V_ms)**2)/2)*(1-(A_1/A_2)**2),2)\n     p1_atm = round(p1/(1.01*10**5),2) # conversion to atmospheres of pressure\n     print('The pressure of the resevoir is', p1, 'N/m^2 or in atm,', p1_atm, 'atm.')\n     ",
 "explanation": "This code uses Bernoulli's principle and equation (3.31) from Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, 6th edition by John Anderson.",
 "reference": "John Anderson, (2017) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, Sixth Edition, McGraw-Hill. Chapter 3.3 Incompressible Flow in a Duct: The Ventury and Low-Speed Wind Tunnel, Example 3.6"
 },

{
 "question": "What is the difference between the Magnus effect and the Coanda effect? Which one is responsible for the floating screwdriver experiment?",
 "answer": "The Coanda effect describes a flow that attaches itself to a curved serface. Imagine a stationary cylinder with a jet of fluid moving around it. As the fluid makes contact with the curved surface, it will \"attach\" itself to the surface and separate further downstream, well after it leaves contact with the cylinder. By contrast, the Magnus effect applies to a cylinder that is rotated in transverse flow and the rotation of the cylinder causes a lift force. The floating screwdriver, as seen in this video by Applied Science: https://youtu.be/jAYP6pWrdkc?si=PZWaAYBoJ9IE_TZp , we can see that the cylinder is not really rotating and is thus acting as a stationary cylinder, thus the Coanda effect is responsible for the flotation of the screwdriver.",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference":""
 },

{
 "question": "What is the speed of sound on Venus?",
 "answer": "\n     import numpy as np\n     import math\n     \n     # The speed of sound is defined by the equation a = sqrt(gamma * R * T)\n     # Assumptions: The atmosphere of Venus is comprised of ideal gases, the temperature of the surface is 740K and atmospheric pressure is 9.32 Mpa\n     gamma = 1.233 # the atmosphere of Venus is mostly comprised of carbon dioxide 96.5% CO2 thus we use gamma for CO2 at roughly 400 C (670 K)\n     T = 740 # average surface temperature in kelvins\n     R = 188.92 # again because the atmosphere is 96.5% carbon dioxide, we assume R to be the value associated with CO2. Units are in J/kg K\n     a = round(math.sqrt(gamma * R * T),2)\n     print('The speed of sound on the surface of Venus is', a,'m/s.')\n     ",
 "explanation" : "This code calculates the speed of sound using the sqrt(gamma R T) definition, since the surface of Venus experiences winds that are upwards of 100 m/s, this code also assumes that all the gases are ideal.",
 "reference": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carbon_dioxide_(data_page) , https://www.engineeringtoolbox.com/individual-universal-gas-constant-d_588.html"
 },

{
 "question": "Why are weak shocks more common than strong shocks?",
 "answer": "Weak shocks are characterized by the mach number post shock remaining above 1. These shocks are preferred in nature as in a weak shock, the angle beta is smaller which is more typical. Strong shocks typically would require the mach number M1 to be very large and for beta to be large compared to a weak shock. This is simply less common in nature as nature does not enjoy a large increase in velocity of a fluid so rapidly.",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference":""
 },

{
 "question": "Consider an oblique shock wave with beta = 35 and a pressure ratio p2/p1 = 3. Calculate the upstream Mach number.",
 "answer": "\n     import numpy as np\n     import math\n     \n     # Use of a table wil help with solving this problem.\n     beta = 35 # given angle in degrees\n     beta_radians = math.radians(beta)\n     p2 = 3\n     p1 = 1 # given ratio is 3/1\n     # Using a table of values, find that when p2/p1 = 3, Mn_1 = 1.64\n     Mn_1 = 1.64 # Mach value rounded to nearest hundredth, found by using table and pressure ratio\n     M1 = round(Mn_1/math.sin(beta_radians),2)\n     print('The Mach number upstream is', M1,'.')\n     ",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference": "John Anderson, (2017) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, Sixth Edition, McGraw-Hill. Chapter 9 Oblique Shock and Expansion Waves, Example 9.4"
 },

{
 "question": "What is the speed of sound through water",
 "answer": "The speed of sound is defined as a = sqrt(gamma * R * T) but water is not a gas, thus that equation cannot be used. Interestingly, gamma for water is 1.0 but there cannot be a constant R for a non gas. From the NOAA (National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration) the speed of sound in water is roughly 1500 m/s)",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference":""
 },

{
 "question": "What can Bernoulli's equation be used for?",
 "answer": "Bernoulli's equation holds for inviscid, incompressible flows, flows along a streamline in rotational flow, and throughout every point in irrotational flow.",
 "explanation":"",
 "reference":""
 },

{
 "question" :"Consider the inviscid, incompressible flow of air along a streamline. The air density along the streamline is0.002377 slug/ft^3, which is standard atmospheric density at sea level. At point 1 on the streamline, the pressure and velocity are 2116 lb/ft^3 and 10 ft/s respectively. Further downstream, at point 2 on the streamline, the velocity is 190 ft/s. Calculate the pressure at point 2",
 "answer": "\n     import numpy as np\n     \n     # This question is prefectly laid out to apply Bernoulli's equation. The flow is incompressible, inviscid and along a streamline thus we can use Bernoulli's equation.\n     p1 = 2116 # pressure upstream at point 1 in lb/ft^2\n     rho = 0.002377 # this is the air density in slug/ft^3\n     V1 = 10 # velocity at point 1 in ft/s\n     V2 = 190 # velocity at point 2 in ft/s\n     p2 = round(p1 + rho*(V1**2-V2**2)*0.5,2)\n     print('The pressure at point 2 is', p2, 'lb/ft^2.')\n     ",
 "explanation": "This code uses Bernoulli's equation to solve for the pressure downstream.",
 "reference": "John Anderson, (2017) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, Sixth Edition, McGraw-Hill. Chapter 3.2 Bernoulli's Equation, Example 3.2"
 },

{
 "question": "Consider the isentropic flow through a convergent-divergent nozzle with an exit-to-throat ratio of 2. The resevoir pressure and temperature are 1 atm and 288 K, respectively. Calculate the Mach number, pressure, and temperature at both the throat and the exit for the cases where (a) the flow is supersonic at the exit.",
 "answer": "\n     import numpy as np\n     \n     # Recognizing that the flow is supersonic at the exit means that the M1 at the throat is 1.\n     M1 = 1\n     p0 = 1 # stagnation pressure in atm\n     T0 = 288 # stagnation temperature\n     p_t = 0.528*p0 # Find the pressure using the ratio of p_star and p0 when M = 1, 0.528 and multiply by p0 recognizing that p_star is the same as p_t\n     T_t = 0.833*T0 # Look up the ratio of T_star/T0 to find that it is 0.833 when M = 1\n     # Recognizing that the area ratio is 2, look at the value tables, for example Appendix A from Fundamentals of Aerodynamics Sixth Edition, find that M_e = 2.2 when A_e/A_star = 2\n     M_e = 2.2\n     p_e = p0/10.69 # when M_e = 2.2 p_e/p0 = 1/10.69 and since p0 = 1 atm, we multiply.\n     T_e = T0/1.968 # When M_e = 2.2, T_e/T0 = 1/1.968 and T0 = 288\n     print('The Mach number at the exit is', M_e,'. The pressure and temperature are', p_t, ' atm and',  T_t,' K respectively.')\n     ",
 "explanation": "Use a table to look up the relevant values according to the area ration, pressure ratio or temperature ratio given and the fact that at the throat, M = 1",
 "reference": "John Anderson, (2017) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, Sixth Edition, McGraw-Hill. Chapter 10 Compressible Flow Through Nozzles, Diffusers, and Wind Tunnels, Example 10.2"
 },

{
"question": "Can sound waves ever propogate non-adiabatically?",
"answer": "Sound does not always travel adiabatically. From Wikipedia: 'The medium in which a sound wave is travelling does not always respond adiabatically, and as a result, the speed of sound can vary with frequency.' These frequencies however, are far outside of what the human ear can perceive, thus for almost all practical applications, the speed of sound is simply  sqrt(gamma R T)",
"explanation":"",
"reference":""
}
]